Guide to the Ruth Steinkraus-Cohen Collection MS 056
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
- Operas/Oratories/Vocal Music
  - Boulez, Pierre, 1925- title: Troisieme sonate pour piano, formant 2, trope Publisher: Universal Edition, 1961 (Box Shelf, Folder 140)
    Vols. I-IV Thomas Morley
  - Buel, James W. 1849-1920, ed. title: The great operas; Vols.1-5 Publisher: Societe Universelle Lyrique, 1899 (Box Shelf, Folder 141-145)
- School Songs and Training Music
  - McNaught, William Gray title: Graduated Rounds for Schools containing ninety-three rounds classified according to range Publisher: Novello and Company, undated (Box 1, Folder 169)
  - Unknown title: Graded Rounds and Catches (Curwen Edition 6079) Publisher: J. Curwen & sons, Ltd., undated (Box 1, Folder 170)
    Staff Notation Edition
  - Tobin, John, 1891-1980 title: The easy descant school song book, selected and edited by John Tobin Publisher: Paterson's, undated (Box 1, Folder 171)
    School Edition
  - Field, Eugene, 1850-1895; DeKoven, Reginald, 1861-1929 title: Songs of childhood Publisher: Scribner's, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 172)
  - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750 Title: Inventions, a deux et a trois parties Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, undated (Box 1, Folder 173)
    Ecole de Piano du Conservatoire Royal de Bruxelles Series
  - DuPont, Auguste, ed. title: Clavecinistes italiens, oeuvres de. G. Frescobaldi, F. Durante, and B. Marcello Publisher: Breitkopf & Hartel, undated (Box 1, Folder 174)
- Photographs
  - Music for a Saturday evening, 1950s (Box 18, Folder 1)
    2 8x 10
  - Gershwin Nite @ Fairfield Hall w/ Edward Bernstein, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    4 8x10
  - Webster Club w/ Barbara Bayne, 1951 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    1 8x10; includes clipping
  - Misc. Portraits / publicity photos, 1940s-1960s (Box 18, Folder 4)
    2 8x10 color; 9 8x10; 1 3x5 (childhood photo w/ brother + sister?); 1 2.5x3.5 (in nurse uniform 1940's)
  - w/ Bob Wilkins WNAB, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    3 8x10; 1 letter
  - Performance + reception, 1950s (Box 18, Folder 6)
    4 8x10;w/ Leopold Godowsky, Odgen Nash, Vernon Pike
  - Performance + reception, 1950s (Box 18, Folder 7)
    6 8x10; w/ Vernon Duke, Ward French
  - w/Aldo Ray @ Symphony Opening, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
    1 8x10
  - HMS Pinafore, 1960s (Box 18, Folder 9)
    2 8x10; Westport, CT
  - w/ Humphrey Doulens, William Steinkraus @ Stonehenge, 1960s (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - w/ unidentified persons, 1960s (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - misc. clippings, etc., undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
    2 greeting cards, 1 telegram
  - misc. U.N. images, 1950s-1960s (Box 18, Folder 13)
    2 8x10, 1 4x6
  - Margery, Billy, Ruth, and Herbert, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    2 8x10
  - w/ Herbert Cohen, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    5 8x10
- Collection information, undated
  - Card catalog, undated (Box 19)
    3 x 5" cards, typed and handwritten that lists books and scores in the collection. Half the cards are in their original order.
  - Notes on composers, undated (Box 19)
    Contains notes regarding opinions on composers perhaps used as notes for interviews. In pencil on 3 x 5" sheets of paper.
  - 3.5 Disk, undated (Box 19)
    Contains Excel file of inventory made perhaps upon Steinkraus' death.